export const CHRISTIANRELIGIOUSSTUDIESA2010 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. On the fourth day, God created the sun, moon and stars for the following purposes except",
A: "to separate the day from the night",
B: "for signs of seasons, days and years",
C: "to give light upon the earth",
D: "to dry up flood from the face of the earth",
answer: "D. to dry up flood from the face of the earth",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following rivers flowed out of Eden to water its garden? River",
A: "Abana",
B: "Pharpar",
C: "Nile",
D: "Pishon",
answer: "D. Pishon",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The wife of Moses was called",
A: "Rebecca",
B: "Rachel",
C: "Zipporah",
D: "Deborah",
answer: "C. Zipporah",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. When Joseph was sent to his brothers, he met them pasturing at",
A: "Hebron",
B: "Bethel",
C: "Beersheba",
D: "Dothan",
answer: "D. Dothan",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. How old was Joshua before he died?",
A: "95 years",
B: "98 years",
C: "110 years",
D: "111 years",
answer: "C. 110 years",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Why was Saul asked to destroy the Amalekites?",
A: "they were worshipping false gods",
B: "they opposed the Israelites when they left Egypt",
C: "They did not assist the Israelites",
D: "God did not like the Amalekites",
answer: "A. they were worshipping false gods",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The first king of Israel lost his throne because he",
A: "was a weak king",
B: "knew little about governance",
C: "lost the support of Yahweh",
D: "was irresponsible",
answer: "C. lost the support of Yahweh",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. During the Ammonite war Uriah disobeyed king David by refusing to go to his house to sleep because",
A: "it was wrong to go home drunk",
B: "his wife would regard him as a coward",
C: "it would be unpatriotic to break military vow",
D: "he suspected that the king had lost interest in the battle",
answer: "C. it would be unpatriotic to break military vow",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Abner wanted to transfer his allegiance to David, the latter gave him the condition to",
A: "openly submit to Joab",
B: "convince all Israel to come over to David",
C: "restore his wife Michal to him",
D: "slay Ishboshet, Saul's successor",
answer: "A. openly submit to Joab",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. God said to Solomon in a dream,'Ask what I shall give you' What did Solomon ask for",
A: "Power and Authority",
B: "Great wealth and riches",
C: "Stable and long term in office",
D: "An understanding mind",
answer: "D. An understanding mind",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Solomon showed lack of wisdom when he",
A: "put up temples for the gods of his wives",
B: "married many wives with children",
C: "invited the Queen of Sheba",
D: "gave out judgement to two harlots",
answer: "A. put up temples for the gods of his wives",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Solomon told Hiram, king of Tyre that he had decided to build a temple for the Lord because",
A: "The Lord had given him peace and all good things",
B: "his father David never intended to build one",
C: "he wanted to force him to come to his aid",
D: "Hiram had entered into a marriage alliance with his father",
answer: "A. The Lord had given him peace and all good things",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Elijah destroyed the prophets of Baal",
A: "to oppose Baal worship",
B: "as an act of revenge",
C: "as an act of sacrifice",
D: "to shame jezebel",
answer: "A. to oppose Baal worship",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Who was the king who reintroduced the passover feast in Israel",
A: "Jeroboam",
B: "Asa",
C: "Josiah",
D: "Rehoboam",
answer: "C. Josiah",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Who was the prophet responsible for the re-building of the Temple during the exile",
A: "Ezra",
B: "Isiaiah",
C: "Jeremiah",
D: "Ezekiel",
answer: "A. Ezra",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following Prophets taught that Yahweh was merciful",
A: "Isaiah",
B: "Hosea",
C: "Amos",
D: "Ezekiel",
answer: "B. Hosea",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Daniel was delivered from the lion's den because",
A: "of his faith in God's power",
B: "of the King's prayers",
C: "he was able to charm the lions",
D: "the lions were kind to him",
answer: "A. of his faith in God's power",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The person who discovered the book of law in the sanctuary during the reign of Josiah was",
A: "Zedekiah",
B: "Huldah",
C: "Hilkiah",
D: "Jeremiah",
answer: "C. Hilkiah",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. According to Amos' prophecy, the 'Day of the Lord' to the Israelites would be a day of",
A: "victory over enemies",
B: "happiness",
C: "doom",
D: "national triumph",
answer: "C. doom",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Isaiah said that when Israel spread forth their hands, God would hide His face because they were",
A: "making many prayers",
B: "offering vain sacrifices",
C: "worshipping God with their hearts",
D: "observing elaborate feasts",
answer: "B. offering vain sacrifices",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. From Luke's account of the baptism of Jesus, which of the following happened before the voice was heard ?",
A: "John was reluctant to baptize him",
B: "John called Jesus the Lamb of God",
C: "Jesus arrived with Peter James and John",
D: "The Holy Spirit descended upon Jesus",
answer: "D. The Holy Spirit descended upon Jesus",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Before their first encounter with Jesus, Peter and Andrew were",
A: "preachers",
B: "tax collectors",
C: "fishermen",
D: "tent makers",
answer: "C. fishermen",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. By the action of the good Samaritan , Christian are encouraged to",
A: "go out to the streets and look for someone to help",
B: "always travel with enough money in case the need arises to help",
C: "show compassion and render help to the needy",
D: "avoid travelling on lonely roads where armed robbers could attack",
answer: "C. show compassion and render help to the needy",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The lost sheep and the Lost Coin share the following except that",
A: "both of them are lost and need to be found",
B: "it is their owner's responsibility to look for them",
C: "the coin, may not know that it is lost",
D: "their owners rejoice when they are found",
answer: "C. the coin, may not know that it is lost",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The parable of the rich man and Lazarus indicates that",
A: "poverty is a mark of righteousness",
B: "death is a leveller for rich and poor",
C: "only poor people will die physically",
D: "all rich men are going to hell fire",
answer: "B. death is a leveller for rich and poor",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. In one of the Resurrection appearances Jesus asked his disciples whether they had anything to eat as he",
A: "was hungry after three days in the grave without food",
B: "suspected that the disciples stock may have finished",
C: "wanted to prove to them that he was not a ghost",
D: "wanted to replenish the food stuff",
answer: "C. wanted to prove to them that he was not a ghost",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. By introducing Jesus as the Lamb, John was pointing to",
A: "Jesus sacrificial death",
B: "Jesus' miraculous healing",
C: "the Jewish yearly sacrifice",
D: "the priestly function of Jesus",
answer: "A. Jesus sacrificial death",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. St. John refers to Jesus' miracles as 'signs' because they convey the following ideas except",
A: "acceptance of Jesus as the Son of God",
B: "proofs of the Kingdom of God",
C: "faith in Jesus as the means to eternal life",
D: "demand for more wonders",
answer: "D. demand for more wonders",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Apart from the miracles at the wedding feast, another miracle of Jesus at Canain Galilee was",
A: "feeding the four thousand",
B: "healing the noble's son",
C: "healing of a man born blind",
D: "healing a paralytic man",
answer: "B. healing the noble's son",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Apart from the miracles at the wedding feast, another miracle of Jesus at Cana in Galilee was",
A: "feeding the four thousand",
B: "healing the noble's son",
C: "healing of a man born blind",
D: "healing a paralytic man",
answer: "B. healing the noble's son",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. At whose well did Jesus meet the Samaritan woman?",
A: "Abraham",
B: "Isaac",
C: "Jacob",
D: "Joseph",
answer: "C. Jacob",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The lame man who was healed at the pool of Bethizatha was charged by the Jews for breaking the law of the Sabbath because he",
A: "consulted Jesus on the Sabbath day",
B: "was carrying his pallet on a Sabbath day",
C: "was on a journey on a Sabbath day",
D: "was seen with Jesus on a Sabbath day",
answer: "B. was carrying his pallet on a Sabbath day",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The descent of the Holy Spirit on the day of Pentecost was prophesied by",
A: "Amos",
B: "Joel",
C: "David",
D: "Ezekiel",
answer: "B. Joel",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. When the apostles in Jerusalem heard that Samaria had received the gospel, they sent to them",
A: "Mark and Barnabas",
B: "Peter and John",
C: "Paul and John",
D: "Peter and Paul",
answer: "B. Peter and John",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The conversion of the Ethiopian eunuch confirms the",
A: "universality of the gospel",
B: "work of the Apostles",
C: "work of Phillip in Samaria",
D: "the love of God for the eunuch",
answer: "A. universality of the gospel",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. After his conversion, Paul was introduced to the disciples in Jerusalem by",
A: "Peter",
B: "Ananias",
C: "Barnabas",
D: "Phillip",
answer: "C. Barnabas",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Before Barnabas and Saul were sent on a missionary journey, the elders laid hands on them. The laying on of hands signifies",
A: "confirmation",
B: "selection",
C: "commissioning",
D: "protection",
answer: "C. commissioning",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The man who delivered the judgement of the Jerusalem Council on the admission of Gentiles into the Church was",
A: "Peter",
B: "Paul",
C: "Barnabas",
D: "James",
answer: "A. Peter",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Why according to Paul must Christians be subject to civil authority?",
A: "To receive God's approval",
B: "to avoid Gd's wrath",
C: "God has commanded it",
D: "it is an Old Testament Law",
answer: "C. God has commanded it",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. In the Epistle to the Romans, justification is received through",
A: "faith in Jesus",
B: "moral uprightness",
C: "observance of the law",
D: "giving of alms",
answer: "A. faith in Jesus",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. By saying that no human being will be justified in the sight of God by works, Paul meant that",
A: "the mosaic law was useless in ensuring justification for man",
B: "the law had been weakened in human flesh",
C: "knowledge of sin came through the law",
D: "Moses who gave the law was not justified by the law",
answer: "A. the mosaic law was useless in ensuring justification for man",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Paul's greatest writing about spiritual gift is found in his letter to the",
A: "Galatians",
B: "Ephesians",
C: "Romans",
D: "Corinthians",
answer: "D. Corinthians",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. In Corinthians, Paul cited all the following resurrection appearances except",
A: "Cephas",
B: "The Twelve",
C: "Mary Magdalene",
D: "James",
answer: "B. The Twelve",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. According to Peter, a Christian should exercise his freedom by",
A: "doing what is right",
B: "claiming his freedom at all cost",
C: "enduring pain while suffering",
D: "using it as a pretext for evil",
answer: "A. doing what is right",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. In which of the following ways did the Philippians share in Paul's suffering while in Prison",
A: "Appealing for the release of Paul",
B: "Sending him relief materials",
C: "Continuing in prayer for him",
D: "Remaining in partnership with him in receiving",
answer: "C. Continuing in prayer for him",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. What advice did Peter give to the elders of the church in their relationship with the younger members?",
A: "work as if being under external constraint",
B: "work without a domineering spirit",
C: "work with a desire for material gains",
D: "control their flock with firm hands",
answer: "B. work without a domineering spirit",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. In Philippians Paul taught that Jesus humility and death on the cross earned him",
A: "salvation for israel",
B: "adoption as son of God",
C: "exaltation as Lord",
D: "eternal life in the kingdom",
answer: "C. exaltation as Lord",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Why did Paul wish to retain Onesimus?",
A: "to protect him from persecution",
B: "Christianity was opposed to slavery",
C: "Philemon had earnestly requested that from Paul",
D: "to serve him during his imprisonment",
answer: "B. Christianity was opposed to slavery",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. James teaches that the man who shall be blessed is he who",
A: "hears the word of God",
B: "knows the law perfectly",
C: "does the word he hears",
D: "teaches the word of God well",
answer: "C. does the word he hears",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Through God the Christian is no longer a slave but a son, and if a son then",
A: "a master",
B: "a redeemed",
C: "an heir",
D: "a beneficiary",
answer: "C. an heir",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question51",
question:  "51. Peter recommends submission to the civil authority so as to",
A: "silence the ungodly",
B: "encourage the believers",
C: "promote faith in God",
D: "live as free men",
answer: "C. promote faith in God",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]